# Divya Velayudhan

Thiruvananthapuram, Kerala, India

@divyavelayudhan2023@gmail.com Ph: 9400318405 linkedin.com/in/divya-velayudhan-278073291



### **Summary**

Currently employed as a Civil Engineer with the Government of Kerala, with seven years of engineering experience in supervision, execution, and teaching. Hold a Master's degree in Traffic and Transportation Engineering. Additionally, possess a creative flair as a content writer and actively pursuing growth in social media content creation, Book tubing, public speaking, and leadership skills. Currently student at Narrative practices India, pursuing Diploma in anticaste mental health practices

# **Experiences**

### **Civil Engineer**

Government of Kerala May 2021- Present

### Writer

Indian Film House
Mar 2024 - Present (1 month)
Article writer in Malayalam at Indian Film House

#### **Author**

Hrudayam Pottippoya kashanangal- Book\_Malayalam poetry
Mar 2024 - Present (1 month)

#### **Author**

Sargakkoodu, a Malayalam book of stories published by Vigil Books.

## **Skills**

Content Development
Content Management
Web Content Writing
Youtuber
Book Reviews
Mentoring
Communication
Community Building

Construction of Buildings and roads - Site Inspections, Proficient in Microsoft Office and AUTOCAD Civil.

Writing, creating poems and short stories, drawing, painting, YouTube content creation, blogging.

#### Associate editor

College magazine at TKMCE (2010, 2011,2012 and 2013).

#### **Head of the Documentation Committee**

At the Indian Society for Technical Education-Students Chapter, TKMCE.

### **Secretary**

of Kerala Varma Memorial Public Library, Kulanada, Pathanamthitta.

#### Media and information committee Head

for the technical fest "Conjura" at TKM College of Engineering.

### **Program Reporter**

for "Conjura-12" for Madhyamam Daily.

### **Magazine Committee member**

at TKM College of Engineering from 2009-2013, contributing to the production of eight magazines

### **Project Manager Civil**

Freelance

Jun 2023 - Present (10 months)

### **Civil Engineer**

Government of Kerala May 2021 - Present (2 years 11 months)

### **Content Developer**

Darpan learning platform
Jan 2020 -Apr 2021 (1 year 4 months)
Content creator for Daily current affairs

#### **Project Engineer**

Government of Kerala Feb 2018 - Mar 2020 (2 years 2 months)Project Engineer at KSCSTE,

# **Education**

### Narrative Practices India

Diploma in Anticaste Mental Health Practices, Mental Health Counseling/Counselor Feb 2024 - Sep 2024

### **College of Engineering Trivandrum**

M Tech in, Traffic and transportation engineering

Jun 2014 - Oct 2016

### TKM College of Engineering, Kollam

B Tech in Civil Engineering, Civil Engineering

Aug 2009 - Dec 2013

#### **NSSHSSPANDALAM**

Higher secondary education
May 2007 - May 2009
87% first class with distinction

#### N S S G H S PANDALAM

May 2003 - Mar 2009 97% Distiction

#### **NATPAC**

### **Teaching Professional**

**Nurture IAS Academy** 

Jan 2018 - Mar 2020 (2 years 3 months)

Teaching faculty for Geography, Environment and Optional Malayalam at Nurture IAS online platform(2018- 2020)

### **Teaching Faculty**

**CIVILIANZ** 

Jan 2017 - Aug 2018 (1 year 8 months)

Tutor at Civilianz, Civil engineering Coaching Centre for General science- SSC JE Coaching (2017-18)

### **Teaching Faculty**

Additional Skill Acquisition Programme

Mar 2016 - Mar 2017 (1 year 1 month)

SDE Skill Develpoment Executive for English and Computer technology for HSE Students, under ASAP Kerala (2016-17)

### **Teaching Faculty**

**Institute of Advanced Studies** 

Jan 2013 - Mar 2014 (1 year 3 months)

Tutor for B tech Civil Engineering subjects (All) at Institute of Advanced studies, Tiruvalla (2013-2014)

I hereby certify that all the information provided in this resume is true and accurate to the best of my knowledge.

Divya Velayudhan